KELLY COLES

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



615-812-2660



kellycoles1@gmail.com



https://github.com/kellycoles



www.linkedin.com/in/kelly-coles1



www.kellycoles.github.io

PROFILE

Having spent 25 years in the transportation industry where creativity, planning, and an engineering mindset are crucial to putting the puzzle together, I developed a passion for problem-solving. Being able to identify problems, break them down to their simplest form and find feasible solutions helped me thrive in my position and in my life.

When I decided to make a career change, software development appealed to me because I love to be challenged, provide solutions, and build things. Through coding, I can build just about anything from the ground up, and the field is ever-changing with opportunities to learn and grow every day.

PROJECTS

The Maintenance Log https://github.com/kellycoles/capstone

The Maintenance Log is an app for anyone who owns anything that requires maintenance or repairs. Users can create a list of items organized by category. They can store details, notes, model numbers, and repair manuals for the items, and log all of the maintenance and repairs performed on the items. Users can access maintenance details on one item or all items. User authentication and persistent storage allow multiple users to store, create, read, edit, and delete their lists of items, and their maintenance lists.

• Built using React, CSS, and JSON server

Nutshell

https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-34/reactivenutshell-ain-t-salty

Nutshell is a dashboard for people to use to organize their daily tasks, events, news article, friends, and chat messages. I collaborated with the team to build user authentication functionality, and I individually developed the Events module achieving CRUD functionality through manipulation of state and fetch calls to JSON server.

• Built using React, CSS, and JSON server

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Web Developer | 2019-Pesent

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp anchoring learning with both individual and team-based projects. Tech Stack: C#/.NET; React.js; Javascript; HTML5; CSS3; SQL

- Built single-page applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React
- Implemented CRUD principles with persistent data storage using JSON server
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub and project managing/tracking with GitHub Projects
- Applied JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY modular, readable code and reusable components
- Application design through whiteboarding dependencies and building ERDs
- Used Agile techniques, such as daily stand ups, code reviews, and sprints in group-based projects to simulate best on-the-job practices
- Utilized LINQ, classes, Inheritance, exception handling, and Interfaces with C#
- Executed SQL queries to extract data from SQL Server databases

OTHER EXPERIENCE

AVERITT EXPRESS

Dock Associate | 2015-2019

- Trained employees to use proprietary software and equipment
- Collaborated with the IT Infrastructure Team about
- networking issues with the WI-FI access points at the Nashville dock
- Made suggestions for improved network connectivity and interference reduction, which were implemented shortly thereafter
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Built and maintained relationships with local customers to generate repeat business}$
- Maintained flawless safety record while working in an extremely fast-paced enviornment

YRC FREIGHT

Dock Associate | 1996-2003

- Contributed to planning more efficient transport routes which resulted in increased profits by reducing fuel costs
- On the safety committee, I aided in planning a major facility overhaul which implemented safer work practices and subsequently decreased work injuries
- Collaborated with customers about better packing solutions to ensure the package contents arrived intact with no damage
- Participated in developing an improved layout and workflow that reduces the number of times the product is handled which reduces the chance of damage and thereby increases company profit

KELLY'S LAWN & LANDSCAPE

Owner/Operator | 2003-2011

- Provided quality lawn care and landscaping to private and commercial properties of Middle Tennessee
- Sub-contracted commercial mowing and landscape maintenance contracts
- Managed accounts payable and receivable
- Managed crews of up to 8 people
- Negotiated commercial and residential contracts
- Coordinated multiple project's schedules while factoring in the availability of workers and material, and changing weather conditions
- Compiled estimates for customers to stay within their budget
- Networked through friends, neighbors, and customers to gain business

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER | 2020

NASHVILLE STATE COMMUNITY COLLEGE

AAS COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS | 2018 magna cum laude